Register of the Victor Gilinsky Papers, 1943-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
- NRC THREE MILE ISLAND INVESTIGATIONS, 1973-1984
  - Environmental effects. Two reports relating to effects on wildlife, 1979 Nov. and 1980 Oct. Material dealing with further effects of decontamination procedures are organized under "Decontamination" (Folder 3)
  - Freedom of Information Act policy, 1979 April-May (Folder 4)
  - General Public Utilities/Metropolitan Edison. Relates primarily to issues of management competence and the restart of the undamaged TMI-1 reactor
    - General
      - General. Organizational charts and information (Folder 5)
      - 1981 Aug. Glenn H. Hutchins, "TMI-1 Management Competence". Report (with drafts and notes) prepared for Dr. Gilinsky (Folder 6-8)
      - 1983 Nov. Edwin H. Stier, "TMI-2 Report: Management and Safety Allegations" Report prepared for GPU Nuclear, with cover letter (Vols. 1-2) (Folder 9-10)
      - 1983 Nov. Stier report contd. (Vol. 3 and Appendix A) (Box 572., Folder 1-3)
    - Cheating incidents
      - General. Investigation reports, 1981 Sept. 30, Oct. 13 and Oct. 28 (Folder 4-6)
      - Examinations (V.V. incident), 1979 July (Box 573., Folder 1)
      - Reports
        - 1982 April. Report of the Special Master assigned by the ASLB, with comments by other interested organizations (Folder 2-4)
        - 1983 Jan. Report prepared by Fred Speaker of Pepper, Hamilton & Scheetz for GPU Nuclear (Folder 5-7)
        - 1983 Jan. Speaker report (contd.). Includes exhibits and various depositions submitted as "Appendix C" (Box 574., Folder 1-3)
    - Core damage. Relates to degree of GPU Nuclear's knowledge of the extent of core damage, 1979 Feb.-1982 Feb. (Folder 4)
    - TMI-1 restart. NOTE: Some of these materials also relate to the management integrity of GPU Nuclear and to the PANE v. NRC lawsuit
      - General
        - General
          - 1979 June-Aug. (Folder 5-8)
          - 1979 Oct.-1980 Oct. (Box 575., Folder 1-10)
          - 1980 Oct.-1981 Feb. (Box 576., Folder 1-8)
          - 1981 March-June (Box 577., Folder 1-8)
          - 1981 June-Aug. Site visit by Dr. Gilinsky, July 1 (Box 578., Folder 1-8)
          - 1981 Aug.-Nov. (Box 579., Folder 1-7)
          - 1981 Dec.-1982 Jan. (Box 580., Folder 1-7)
          - 1982 Jan.-Feb. NRC-sponsored workshop relating to psychological stress issues, Feb. 4-5 (Box 581., Folder 1-7)
          - 1982 Feb.-March (Box 582., Folder 1-9)
          - 1982 April-July (Box 583., Folder 1-7)
          - 1982 July-Oct. (Box 584., Folder 1-8)
          - 1982 Nov. Site visit, Nov. 1; public meeting, Nov. 9; public comments, ca. Nov. 17 (Box 585., Folder 1-7)
          - 1982 Nov.-Dec. Public comments (contd.) (Box 586., Folder 1-8)
          - 1982 Dec.-Jan. Report by the Franklin Research Center, "Technical Evaluation Report: Review of Licensees' Resolution of Outstanding Issues from NRC Equipment Environmental Qualification Safety Evaluation Reports (F-11 and B-60)--Metropolitan Edison Company, Three Mile Island Nuclear Station Unit 1" (2 vols.) (Box 587., Folder 1-10)
          - 1983 Jan.-March. Investigation reports, Feb. 28 and March 21 (Box 588., Folder 1-8)
          - 1983 March-May. Parks allegations, March 23 (Box 589., Folder 1-9)
          - 1983 May-June. Gilinsky opinion, June 22 (Box 590., Folder 1-9)
          - 1983 June-Sept. Enforcement action proposed, July 22 (Box 591., Folder 1-8)
          - 1983 Sept.-Oct. Inspection report relating to leak rate testing, Oct. 6 (Hartman allegations) (Box 592., Folder 1-8)
          - 1983 Oct.-Nov. Grand Jury indictment of Metropolitan Edison for criminal misconduct, Nov. 7 (Box 593., Folder 1-8)
          - 1983 Nov.-Dec. Senate hearings (Sen. Arlen Specter, Chairman), Dec. 16; investigation report, Dec. 21 (Box 594., Folder 1-9)
          - 1983 Dec.-1984 Jan. (Box 595., Folder 1-8)
          - 1984 Feb. (Box 596., Folder 1-8)
          - 1984 March-April (Box 597., Folder 1-9)
          - 1984 April-May (Box 598., Folder 1-9)
          - 1984 June (Box 599., Folder 1-4)
        - Meeting transcripts
          - 1980 Nov. 8-9 (Folder 5-6)
          - 1980 Nov. 10-17 (Box 600., Folder 1-5)
          - 1980 Feb. 13-Aug. 13 (Box 601., Folder 1-6)
          - 1980 Oct. 15-22 (Box 602., Folder 1-5)
          - 1980 Oct. 23-31 (Box 603., Folder 1-6)
          - 1980 Nov. 4-12 (Box 604., Folder 1-6)
          - 1980 Nov. 13-21 (Box 605., Folder 1-6)
          - 1980 Nov. 24-Dec. 3 (Box 606., Folder 1-5)
          - 1980 Dec. 4-12 (Box 607., Folder 1-5)
          - 1980 Dec. 16-22 (Box 608., Folder 1-5)
          - 1980 Dec. 23-1981 Jan. 14 (Box 609., Folder 1-6)
          - 1981 Jan. 15-28 (Box 610., Folder 1-6)
          - 1981 Feb. 3-11 (Box 611., Folder 1-5)
          - 1981 Feb. 12-19 (Box 612., Folder 1-5)
          - 1981 Feb. 20-March 4 (Box 613., Folder 1-5)
          - 1981 March 5-17 (Box 614., Folder 1-6)
          - 1981 March 18-31 (Box 615., Folder 1-8)
          - 1981 April 1-8 (Box 616., Folder 1-7)
          - 1981 April 9-22 (Box 617., Folder 1-7)
          - 1981 April 23-May 1 (Box 618., Folder 1-6)
        - Partial Initial Decisions
          - 1981 Aug. 27. "Procedural Background and Management Issues" (Folder 7)
          - 1981 Dec. 14 (Vol. 1) "Plant Design and Procedures and Separation Issues" (Box 619., Folder 1)
          - 1981 Dec. 14 (Vol. 2) "Emergency Planning Issues" (Folder 2)
          - 1982 July 27. "Reopened Proceedings" (Folder 3)
      - Hartman allegations. Relates to allegations by Harold W. Hartman, Jr. relating to the falsification of the results of reactor coolant surveillance leak rate tests
        - 1980-1983 May. Includes investigation report (1980 Sept.) by Faegre & Benson (law firm?) as an attachment to a 1983 March 23 memorandum; inspection report, 1983 May 18 (Folder 4-7)
        - 1983 May-1984 Feb. Letter to Congressman Udall from NRC Chairman Palladino (with extensive attachments), Feb. 6 (Box 620., Folder 1-7)
        - 1984 Feb. Udall letter (contd.) (Box 621., Folder 1-2)
      - Hydrogen burn/detonation. Transcripts and report by H.W. Schutz and P.K. Nagata (E.G. & G. Idaho, Inc.) entitled, "Estimated Temperatures of Organic Materials in the TMI-2 Reactor Building during Hydrogen Burn", 1979 May-1982 Dec. (Folder 3)
  - International reactions, 1979 March-1980 Feb. (Folder 4)
  - Investigation and enforcement
    - General. Primarily material relating to internal NRC investigations; also includes very preliminary material relating to the establishment of an external investigation (Rogovin Commission)
      - 1979 March-Aug. (Folder 5-9)
      - 1979 Aug.-1981 May (Box 622., Folder 1-10)
      - 1981 May-1982 Feb. Summary of enforcement actions against Met Ed, 1981 Oct. 13 (Box 623., Folder 1-3)
    - Reports
      - 1979 Aug. "Investigation into the March 28, 1979 Three Mile Island Accident by Office of Inspection and Enforcement" (NUREG 0600)
        - General. NRC comparative review of the 1979 July 15 draft with the final report, 1983 Sept. (Folder 4-9)
        - General. Comparative review (contd.) (Box 624., Folder 1)
        - Final report (Folder 2)
      - 1980 Dec. "Reporting of Information Concerning the Accident at Three Mile Island". Attributed to H. Myers, but probably related to the following investigation (Folder 3-4)
      - 1981 Jan. "Investigation into Information Flow during the Accident at Three Mile Island" (NUREG 0760)
        - General, 1979 May-1982 March (Box 625., Folder 1-5)
        - Depositions
          - Chwastyk, Joseph (1980 Sept. 4) (Folder 6)
          - Dieckamp, Herman M. (1980 Sept. 12) (Folder 7)
          - Herbein, John (1980 Sept. 5) (Folder 8)
          - Miller, Gary Paul (1980 Sept. 5) (Folder 9)
        - Report
          - Draft (three copies with different annotations) (Box 626., Folder 1-3)
          - Report (advance copy and final copy) (Folder 4-6)
          - Report (appendices) (Box 627., Folder 1-2)
  - Radiation health effects, 1979 April-1984 April. Includes a report by the Committee on the Biological Effects of Ionizing Radiations, National Academy of the Sciences, "The Effects on Populations of Exposure to Low Levels of Ionizing Radiations," May 2; Glenn/Percy Committee hearings, May 3 and May 9; joint House Committee hearing, June 13; a table on the TMI Radiological Sequence of Events, June 14; information on xenon (report by Jerry Pollack), 1979 Sept.-0ct.; "Report of the Special Panel on Three Mile Island Unit 2 Radiation Protection Program," 1979 Dec. 7 (Folder 3-7)
  - Social and psychological effects. Three Mile Island telephone survey, 1979 Sept. and a report entitled, "The Social and Economic Effects of the Accident at Three Mile Island" (NUREG/CR 1215), 1980 Jan. (Box 628., Folder 1)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1943-1984
  - General, 1975-1981 (Box 628., Folder 2)
  - Alexander L. Kielland (North Sea oil platform). Relates to an accident, March 27, 1980. Memorandum and report, 1981 (Folder 3)
  - American Telephone and Telegraph divestiture. Opinion, 1982 (Folder 4)
  - Atomic Industrial Forum (AIF). Relates to briefings before the NRC, 1978-1983 (Folder 5)
  - Department of Energy (DOE)
    - General, 1979-1984. Includes a report entitled, "A Safety Assessment of Department of Energy Nuclear Reactors" (Folder 6)
    - Laboratories. NRC memoranda, 1980 (Folder 7)
  - Economics of nuclear energy
    - General
      - 1975-1976 (Folder 8)
      - 1978-1982 (Box 629., Folder 1)
    - Shutdowns and delays, 1979-1982 (Folder 2-3)
  - Energy projections
    - General
      - 1967-1980 (Folder 4-8)
      - 1981-1984 (Box 630., Folder 1-3)
    - Nuclear, 1975-1982 (Folder 4-8)
  - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI). Memorandum relating to inter-agency cooperation, 1975 (Folder 9)
  - Mobil Oil Company, 1978-1979. Advertisements (Folder 10)
  - Presidential policy
    - Ford, Gerald R. Speech transcripts, memoranda, letter, 1975-1977 (Box 631., Folder 1)
    - Carter, James E.
      - General, 1976-1980. Speech transcripts, memoranda, clippings, letter (Folder 2-8)
      - Schlesinger, James R. Speech transcripts, printed articles, letter, 1966-1977 (Folder 9)
    - Reagan, Ronald. Memoranda, clippings, speech transcripts, letters
      - 1980 (Folder 10)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 632., Folder 1-2)
  - Supreme Court decisions
    - PG&E vs. [California] State Energy Resources Conservation and Development Commission et al., 1983 (Folder 3)
    - Silkwood vs. Kerr-McGee, 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Tennessee Valley Authority (TVA). Statements and report, 1979-1982 (Folder 5)
  - Weapons. Relates to nuclear weapons construction, proliferation and arms control. Includes materials by George W. Rathjens, Jr. and Admiral Noel Gayler, lecture notes from the Manhattan Project, Los Alamos, New Mexico, and a pastoral letter by the U.S. Bishops on War and Peace. Printed articles, reports, memoranda and letters, 1943-1983 (Folder 6-7)
  - Westinghouse. Relates to a site visit and presentation, 1979 Nov.-1984 Jan. (Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1981-1983.
  - Computer printouts summarizing Licensee Event Reports for the Sequoyah, Grand Gulf and Quad Cities nuclear power plants, a report entitled, "Licensed Fuel Facility Status Report," Vol. 1, No. 6 (NUREG-0430), a resolution by the Pennsylvania State Senate, a map of the area around the San Onofre nuclear power plant, and versions of a chart relating to the construction permit for the Midland nuclear power plant. (Box 633.)
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - See photo card catalog for description. (Box 10.A-V)